화이트칼라 지난 이야기...
Previously on "White collar"...
우리의 최고이자 마지막 목표를 위하여
To our best, and final score.
이게 뭔가?
- What is it? - Part of the original
German u-boat manifest.
독일 유보트에서 나온
부분 적하목록 입니다
아직도 카프리가 미술품을
가지고 있다고 생각하시나요?
- You think Caffrey has the art?
- I don't know.
모르겠어
크라머 요원님이 직접 오지 못해
미안해 하고있습니다
Agent Kramer is sorry he can't be here
in person, but he brieffed me fully.
하지만 제게 충분히 설명해주었죠
다 설명해주었다구요?
He did?
- 크리스 게이츠입니다
- 인터폴이세요?
- Chris gates.
- You're interpol?
네
Yeah.
그럼 이게 부분 목록이군요
So it's a partial list.
침몰함에 있던 대부분의 것들은
아직 발견되지 않았군요
Most of what was on the sub
is still unaccounted for.
그들은 한 페이지만 찾았죠
They only found one page.
하지만, 누군가 그 리스트에 있는 것 중
하나라도 팔게 된다면...
If anyone tries to sell anything that's
on that list we're gonna nail them.
소식을 듣게 되겠군요
Yes, we are.
금고는 찾았어?
Did you find the safe?
목록은 거기에 없었어
모즈, 미안해
The manifest wasn't in here.
Moz, I'm sorry.
켈러 '사냥 허가' 기간입니다
전리품은 승자에게 돌아갈겁니다
It's open season on Keller.
Spoils go to the Victor.
600만 달러 포상금이라
A $6 million bounty.
암시장에 드가를 팔았을 때와
비슷한 가격인것 같아
That's roughly the black-market
sale price of the Degas.
아냐. '정확히' 드가를
팔았을 때의 가격이지
No. That's the exact sale price
of the Degas.
그게 목록에 있다고, 모즈!
It's on the list, Moz!
거짓말 한거야?
You lied to me?
드가가 나타나면 FBI는
보물이 타지 않았다는 걸 알게 될꺼야
When the Degas turns up --
and it will --
the FBI is gonna know
the treasure didn't burn,
우리가 주요 용의자라구
and we are the prime suspects.
참새는 자정에 죽습니다
The sparrow dies at midnight.
그럼 난 참새하기 싫어질 것 같은데
Then I'd hate
to be the sparrow.
진심이야?
Seriously?
북미연합의 리더를 만날
예정이었단 말이야
I was about to expose the leader
of the North American Union.
아니. 그건 네 생각일 뿐이야
Nope.
You just thought you were.
북미연합은 존재하지 않아
The N.A.U. doesn't exist.
설마. 니가 이걸 꾸민거야?
Says you.
You set this up?
어떻게든 너랑 얘기해야 했어
I had to talk to you somehow.
또 다른 거짓말로 말이지
Another piece of fiction.
FBI가 가진 미술 목록이 없다는
이야기를 길게 늘어놓는 것 처럼 말야
Much like the yarn you spun
about not having
the FBI's art manifest.
넌 화낼 권리가 있어
내가 거짓말을 했어
You have a right to be angry.
I lied to you.
왜?
Why?
요원님의 금고를 털었고
I broke into Peter's safe.
내 손에 목록이 있었지
I had the list in my hand.
보물을 가지고 떠날 준비가 되어 있었어
I was ready to take
the treasure and go.
근데 왜 그랬어?
Then why didn't you?
요원님이 전화..
Peter cal--
여기에서의 삶이 있다구
I have a life here.
하지만 우린 꿈이 있잖아
But we had a dream.
뭐, 꿈은 바뀔 수도 있어
Well, dreams change.
내 말은, 느긋하게 시간을 보내는게
싫어지면 어떡할지 생각해봤어?
I mean, have you ever thought
we might not like
whiling away our days
지중해 섬 한가운데서 말야
on a mediterranean island?
그럼 우리 섬을 팔고
돌아오면 되잖아
Then we sell our island
and come back.
넌 돌아올 수 있지만
난 못해
No, you can come back.
I can't.
한번 떠나면
I run on this,
뉴욕은 그냥 기억속에
머물러 있을 뿐이야
and New York
is just a memory for me.
왜 그래, 닐
Come on, Neal.
이게 바로..
This was the one--
완벽한 마지막 득점이라구
the perfect last score.
네가 망설일 줄 알았어
I knew you were
dragging your feet.
나 몰래 드가를 팔았잖아
You went behind my back
and fenced the Degas.
난..
I did it to--
난 우리를 지키려고 했어
I did it to protect us.
켈러에게 포상금을 거는걸로?
By putting a hit on Keller?
그렇게 성급하게 행동하는게 바로
우리를 문제에 빠트리는 길이야
Doing something that rash
is exactly what
will get us into trouble.
대부분의 암시장 물건은
다시 나타나지 않아. 너도 알잖아
Most black-market pieces
never resurface. You know that.
요원님이 찾고있는
목록에는 없기 때문이야
Because they're not on a list
that Peter
is actively looking for.
하지만 드가는
요원님이 찾아 낼거야
The Degas is.
If Peter finds it--
그래, 알아
Yeah, I know.
보물이 타지 않았다는 걸 알게 되겠지
And it proves that
the treasure didn't burn,
모든 관심은 우리에게 돌아올꺼고
and the trail leads
straight back to us.
그러니 시간 낭비는 그만 하자
누가 장물아비야?
So let's stop the bleeding.
Who's the fence?
러스티
Rusty.
러스티? 정말?
Rusty? Seriously?
좋아, 그에게 물어서
All right, talk to him.
누가 그 그림을 사 갔는지 알아내자
Find out who
he sold the painting to.
거기서 부터 시작하는거야
We'll start there.
좋아
Fine.
러스티랑 얘기해봐, 알았지?
Talk to Rusty, okay?
하지만, 한가지 질문이 남아있어
But that does leave
one question.
여기 머물길 원해?
Do you want to stay?
알게 해줄게
I'll let you know.
명예롭게 사는 가장 좋은 방법은
The greatest way
to live honorably
그런 척을 하면서 사는거네
is to be what we pretend to be.
하지만 바꿔 말하면
I'm paraphrasing,
늙은 소크라테스는
그렇게 생각하지 않을 걸세
but I don't think
old Socrates here would mind.
그렇겠죠
He might.
Can I help you?
- 제가 도와드릴 거라도 있나요?
- 그래
Yeah.
르네상스 초상화 메달에 대해서
뭔가 아는게 있는가?
You know anything about
renaissance portrait medals?
제가 알고 있으리라
짐작 하시는군요
You seem to know that I do.
8년전 스미소니언에서 도둑 맞은
피오렌티노에 대한 미해결 사건이 있어
I have a cold case
on a Fiorentino
that was taken from
the Smithsonian 8 years ago.
내가 찾아낸 건 포장지로 둘러쌓인
초콜렛으로 밝혀졌지
The one I found turned out to be
chocolate, wrapped in foil.
이 이야기 들어 봤을 텐데
You probably heard that story.
어딘가 친근하게 들리네요
Sounds vaguely familiar.
그럴 줄 알았네
I thought it might.
- 난..
- 크라머 요원님
- I'm--
- Agent Kramer,
DC 미술 범죄국 국장님이시죠
head of the Bureau's
D.C. Art Crimes unit.
지금이 필연적인 순간이라고
말하고 싶네, 미스터 카프리
I'd say this moment
was inevitable, Mr. Caffrey,
내가 누군지, 네가 누군지
주고 받는 것 말야
given I am who I am,
and you are who you are.
좋네요
둘이 먼저 만났군요
Oh, good.
You two have met.
닐과 나는, 음..
Oh, Neal and I were, uh...
글쎄, 우리가 뭘 하고 있었던거지?
Well, what were we doing here?
그냥 수다 떨고 있었죠
Shooting the breeze.
그래.
그렇게 말할 수 있겠네
Yeah.
Yeah, you could say that.
크라머 요원님은 콴티코에 있을때 내 멘토였어
(Quantico : 버지니아주 북동부의 해병대 기지)
Agent Kramer was
my mentor at Quantico.
지금은 그냥 친구지
Now I'm a just a friend.
피터 요원님이 알고있는 모든 것을
가르치신 분이시군요
So you're the one who taught
Peter everything he knows.
- 어느정도는 그렇지
- 으흠
- Well, I taught him a fair amount.
- Mm-hmm.
몇 가지는 빼고 말이야
Kept a few things for myself.
그건 말 안하셨잖아요
Oh, now, you didn't tell me that.
DC 에서 뉴욕까지 오신 이유가 뭔가요?
What brings D.C. to New York?
자네가 말해주겠나?
You tell him?
회의실에 가서 이야기 하는게 어때?
Why don't we take this
into the conference room?
음
Mm.
좋아요
All right.
이틀 전, 제보를 받았다
Two days ago, we got a tip
뉴욕에서 오래된 명작이
표면으로 나왔다
that a long-lost masterpiece
surfaced in New York.
모두 크라머 요원이 DC 에서
온 건 알고 있을거다
You all know
Agent Kramer from D.C.
우리의 정보원 중 한명이 암시장에서
그림이 팔린다는 정보를 입수했다
One of our C.I.s
heard chatter
of a black-market painting
being sold here.
'드가'이군요
A Degas.
안목 좋은데, 존스
Good eye, Jones.
"가면 쓴 댄서의 등장"
이라고 불리는 거지
This one's called "Entrance
of the masked dancers."
이건 완성..
It was compl--
닐. 여기서 부터는
네가 말해도 되겠구나
Oh, Neal, I'm sure
you can take it from here.
오, 1884년에 완성됬고
Oh, completed in 1884,
드가의 중요한 작품중 하나죠
it's one of Degas'
seminal works.
그가 유명해진 "엷은 옷의 발레리나들"
보다 더 복잡하죠
It's more complex than the gauzy
ballerinas he's famous for.
이 작품은 41년에 독일로
이동되었다고 알려져있다
It's believed to have been
taken by the Germans in '41
성 페테르부르크에 있는
트라르스코 셀로 박물관에서 말이다
from the Tsarskoye Selo museum
in Saint Petersburg,
다른 작품들과 마찬가지로
along with a whole lot
of other art.
그떄 이후로 나타나지 않았지
It hasn't been seen since.
어떻게 생각하나, 닐?
What do you think, Neal?
저요?
Me?
이런 명작을 되찾는다는 건
대단한 일이라고 생각합니다
I think recovering
this masterpiece
would be incredible, sir.
나도
Me too.
이걸 찾아 낼 거야
So we're gonna find it.
모즈, 러스티랑 얘기 해 봤어?
Hey, Moz, did you talk to Rusty?
전갈을 남겼는데
돌아온 건 없어
I left word.
He hasn't returned.
진정해. 포코노스로 등산이나 갔겠지
(Poconos : 펜실베니아에 위치한 산 이름)
Relax.
He goes up to the Poconos.
FBI가 드가에 대해 알고 있어
The FBI knows about the Degas.
- 우리의 드가?
- 우리의 드가였지
- Our Degas?
- Well, as much as it ever was.
러스티를 찾아서 우리의 이름이
새나가지 않도록 해야해
We have to find Rusty, make sure
he keeps our names out of this.
가설이 현실이 됬네
Oh, the hypothetical
becomes the reality.
글쎄, 현실이 어떨까?
Well, how's this for reality?
크라머 요원이 DC에서
피터 요원님의 요청을 받고 왔어
Agent Kramer is in town from D.C.,
lending Peter a hand.
정말?
Really?
미술 범죄국의 앞잡이는 어때 보이는데?
What's the eminence grise
of the art crimes unit like?
요원님께 다년간의 경험을
전수해 주었고
Take Peter,
add years of experience
우리를 느슨하게 대하려는
성향은 없어
and less inclination
to cut us slack.
내 피가 다 차가워 지는데
My blood just ran cold.
아마 인상파에 대해서
폭 넓은 지식을 가지고 있겠네
Supposedly he has
an encyclopedic knowledge
of the impressionists.
내가 놀랄 만큼 드가에 대한
지식을 가지고 있어
Well, he knows enough
about our Degas
to scare the hell out of me.
제발 그 '금요일 여자'는
안 데려왔다고 말해줘
Please tell me he didn't bring
his girl Friday with him.
운이 좋았어.
매튜 요원은 함께 오지 않았어
No, we caught a break.
Agent Matthews isn't with him.
다행이네, 사실 난
어떻게 해결해야 할지 몰랐거든
A break, indeed. I don't know how
you would have gotten out of that.
이걸 빠져나가는 것에 집중하자
Well, let's focus
on getting out of this.
요원님이 그림 찾는 걸
멈추게 해야해
We need to stop Peter
from finding that painting.
생각해 놓은게 있어?
What do you have in mind?
드가를 찾아 다시 가지고 와야지
Locate the Degas
and get it back.
근데 왜 내 탁자에
거대한 모래시계가 있는거야?
Why is there a giant hourglass
on my table?
어느 시점에선가
네 동기가 흐려질까봐서야
Somewhere along the line,
I think your motives got blurred.
보물을 계속 가지고 있는건
절대 장기적 계획이 아니야
Keeping the treasure here
was never part
of the long-term plan.
- 모즈, 이건..
- 48 시간
- Moz, this is not--
- 48 hours.
그 땐, 우리가 떠나기에 필요하다고
생각되는 모든 걸 할꺼야
In that time, I will do anything
you think we need to do
in order to leave.
시간이 다 되면?
And when time runs out?
롤라나와 내가
Lolana and I
보물을 가지고 떠날꺼야
are taking the treasure
and leaving...
목록이나, 드가나
FBI에 상관없이 말이야
Regardless of the list,
the Degas, or the FBI.
우리와 함께 가길 바랄게
I hope you'll come with us.
최후 통보를 하는 거잖아
You're giving me an ultimatum.
그래, 맞아
Yes, I am.
여기서 피터 요원님과 같이 있던지
아님 나와 함께 가던지
Stay here with Peter
or come with me.
결정해, 닐
Choose a side, Neal.
Sync by Gatto, corrected by gloriabg
www.addic7ed.com
한글자막 : EzLoves
블로그 : vstu77.blog.me
오타, 오역 등 피드백 남겨주세요!
Sync by Gatto, corrected by gloriabg
www.addic7ed.com
WHITECOLLAR
S03E10 Countdown
ORIGINAL DATE 2011/08/09
CREATED BY
JEFF EASTIN
네, 흥미로운 사건이네요
Yeah, that was an interesting one.
마피아 보스에게 전화사기를 쳤었어
We pulled the wire con
on a mob boss.
뉴욕 화이트칼라 사무실의
또 다른 평범한 날이지
Another average day
in the New York
White Collar office.
웃지 마, 크게 틀리진 않아
- Don't laugh. It's not far off.
- Mnh-mnh.
절제력 있고 이성적인 네게
무슨 일이 벌어진거야?
What happened to the stoic,
no-nonsense probie
고고학자라고도 불렸었잖아
we called The Archeologist?
고고학자라구요?
The Archeologist?
맞아, 한번 파면 멈추지 않았지
Yeah, he'd never stop digging.
전 아직 절제주의자에요
I'm still stoic.
- 음, 닐이 자길 좀 느슨하게 만든 것 같은데
- 아니야
- Well, Neal's loosened you up
a little bit. - Not true.
- 나도 그런 것 같은데
- 좋은 쪽으로요
- I can see that.
- But in a good way.
우리의 사건 해결률은
전례가 없을 정도라구요
Hey, our closure rate
is unprecedented.
DC 에서도 자네들에 대해
알고 있어
They know
about you boys in D.C.
많은 말들을 한다구
Lot of water-cooler talk
고담시의 '경찰과 도둑'으로 불리고 있지
about Gotham City's
finest cop and robber.
주방에 이 사진을 놓아 뒀던데
You took this right here
in the kitchen.
맞아요. 네.
닐은 제 컨설턴트구요.. 그는
Yeah. Yeah.
Neal is my C.I., and he's --
그래, 또한 친구이기도 하지
Yeah, he's also a friend.
음, 난 커피 주전자에
물 좀 올려놓고 올게
I'm-- I'm-- I'm gonna go
put a pot of coffee on,
이야기 하고 있어, 알았지?
and I'll let you guys talk, okay?
드가를 훔쳤다고 생각하는 그 녀석과
엄청 가까이 지내는 구만
You're awful close to the guy
you think stole the Degas.
그렇게 보이나요?
It's that obvious?
오늘 사람 많은 회의실에서
그림에 대해 얘기할 때
Well, today you had
a room full of people
ready to go
after that painting,
and you looked at only one man.
넌 한 사람만 보고 있었어.
그가 보물을 훔쳤다고 생각하나?
You think he stole the treasure?
그런 느낌이 든다구요
I have my suspicions.
그게 제가 도움을 요청 한 이유구요
That's why you're here.
바깥의 관점이 필요해요
I need an outside perspective.
내가 널 만나기 전에
Hey, before I met you,
아들의 작은 리그팀에서 야구 연습을
도와주던 컨설턴트가 있었어
I had a C.I. who used
to throw batting practice
for my son's
little league team.
지금은요?
And now?
지금은 가끔 감옥에서 온
이메일을 받곤 하지
Now I get the
occasional e-mail from prison.
이건 단지 단기적인
관계 일 뿐이야
These are short-term
relationships, Petey, at best.
그들의 뇌가 그렇게 동작 한다고
It's hardwired in their brains.
한 번 사기꾼인 사람은
영원한 사기꾼이라고 생각 하시나요?
You think once a con,
always a con?
I think recidivism rates
paint a bleak picture.
재범 비율은 상당히 높다고 생각해
그가 타락할 때
넌 스스로를 보호 해야 해
And you have to protect yourself
when they fall.
알아요, 제 직업이 위험해 지겠죠
I know.
My career's at risk.
아니, 네 직업에 대한게 아냐
No, I'm not talking
about your job.
너에 대해서 이야기 하는거야
I'm talking about you.
그 일이 벌어지면
When this happens,
범죄자에게 수갑을 채우는게 아니라
you're not slapping cuffs
on a criminal.
친구를 잡아 넣는거야
You're taking down a friend.
가슴 아프지
It hurts.
사람은 바뀔 수 있어요
People can change.
피티..
Pete...
네 도움을 요청했잖아
you asked me for my help.
닐이 용의자라면..
If Neal is a suspect...
He is.
그럼 용의자처럼 대해야 해
...then you have
to treat him like one.
닐, 너의 전문 지식이 필요해
Neal, we need your expertise.
그게 제가 여기 있는 이유겠죠
That's what I'm here for.
Great.
좋아
네가 70년 전에 사라진
명작들을 가지고 있다고 해보자
Let's say
that you're in possession
of a masterpiece
that disappeared 70 years ago.
Like a Degas?
- 드가 같은 거요?
- 그렇지
Exactly.
넌 상상해 볼 수 있잖아
그렇지, 닐?
You can imagine that,
right, Neal?
우리가 말한 상상을
즐기는 거죠, 요원님
Enjoying the fantasy
as we speak, sir.
- 오래 가지 못해서 안타깝네
- 왜요?
- Too bad it can't last.
- Why not?
위험한 그림이거든.
당장 없애야 해
Because the painting's hot.
You have to get rid of it.
- FBI가 절 잡기 전에요?
- 정확해
Or the feds will take me down?
Exactly.
받아야 하나?
(30분 내에 러스티와의 만남)
You need to take that?
Nope.
아니요
제가 위험한 드가를 가지고 있고
잡히기 전에 옮겨야 겠네요
So I've got a hot Degas I need
to move before you take me down.
질문은, 어떻게 그걸 팔거냐지
Question is,
how do you fence it?
- 전 안해요. 대신 팔아줄 누군가가 있겠죠
- 왜 중개인을 끼려고 하지?
I don't. I'd have someone
fence it for me.
Why go through a middleman?
드가가 나타난다면 많은
회의론자들이 그림을 알게될꺼에요
A Degas appearing
after all this time
is going to be greeted with
a healthy amount of skepticism.
사람들은 위조라고 생각할텐데
People will assume
it's a forgery.
맞아요, 보통 그러죠
Yeah, they usually are.
팔려면 명성이 높은 사람이 필요하죠.
제가 찾아보길 원하시나요?
So I'd need someone with an impeccable
reputation to make the sale.
You want me to ask around?
사실, 크라머의 팀이 이미
두명의 용의자를 찾았어
Actually, Kramer's team already
has two suspects in mind.
철저한데요
Thorough.
거스 릴랜드야
This is Gus Leland.
인상파 그림을 독점 거래하고
최근에 뉴욕으로 돌아왔지
Deals exclusively
in French impressionists,
recently returned to New York.
거스 알아요.
항상 우수한 작업을 하죠
I know Gus.
He always has quality work.
딱 맞겠네요
He definitely fits the bill.
두번째는 러스티라고 알려진 놈이야
Second guy is known as Rusty.
흠잡을데 없는
위조 감별을 하는 놈이지
Renowned for an impeccable eye
at spotting forgeries.
네, 그도 암시장 거래의
브로커 용의자 일 수 있죠
Yeah, he's suspected of
brokering the black-market sale
작년에 나온 마티즈의
"전원곡(La pastorale)"도 포함해서요
of Matisse's
"La pastorale" last year.
Yeah.
그래
그리고 여기서 최고의 그림을
판다는 소문이 났지
And it's also rumored
he recently sold
a high-priority painting here.
- 음
- 말해보게, 닐
- Mm.
- Tell me, Neal,
자네가 드가를 팔려면
when you fence your Degas,
누구를 통해서 하겠나?
who are you gonna use?
러스티는 지역 연락망이 있죠
Rusty's got the local contacts.
저라면 러스티를 통해서 하겠어요
I'd go with Rusty.
그럼 그를 쫓아야겠네
Then that's who we'll go after.
좋아, 내 팀은 거스를 쫓는다
Okay.
My team has Gus.
행운을 비네
Good luck, gentlemen.
좋아요, 모지에게 전화해볼게요
All right, I'll call Mozzie.
암시장의 엘리트들을 꿰고 있거든요
He keeps tabs
on Gotham's black-market elite.
필요없어. 러스티를 24시간 감시 중이야
No need. We've had eyes
on Rusty for 24 hours.
어디있는지 정확히 알고 있어
We know exactly where he is.
가자
Let's go.
걸어가자
Let's walk.
러스티를 데려갈 차가 필요하지 않나요?
Don't we need a car
to pick up Rusty?
몇 대 대기해놨어
I got a few in place.
누군가에게 접근하거나
연락 해야 하나?
Need to reach out
and touch someone?
뭐 간단한 도구만 있으면
급변하는 세계와 어깨를 나란히 할 수 있죠
I find it a handy tool
to keep abreast
in this fast-paced world.
그럴 필요 없어.
넣어둬
No one ever talks anymore.
Put that away.
얘기하자고
Let's talk.
좋아요
Okay.
크라머 요원님이 왜 여기 있는지 말해주세요
Tell me why
Kramer's really here.
그는 친구이자 멘토야
He's a friend
and he's a mentor.
감시인이기도 하구요
He's a watchdog.
멘토란게 그런거라고 생각하는거야?
Is that what you think
a mentor is?
호머의 오딧세이에도
묘사 되어있어요
Let's see-- as depicted
in Homer's "Odyssey,"
멘토는 반신반인이라고요
mentor was half-man-half-God.
내 기억으론 그가
연합군의 목표이자 길이었지
He represented the union
of path and goal, if I recall.
지혜의 화신이야
Wisdom personified.
그렇게도 해석 가능하군요
That's one interpretation.
멘토는 트로이잔 전투에서
오딧세이의 아들을 이끌었죠
Mentor also guided Odysseus' son
during the Trojan war.
전쟁하시게요, 요원님?
You planning
to go to war, Peter?
오, 아직은 아니야
Oh, not yet.
하지만 해야 한다면
크라머 요원이 내 뒤를 봐줄꺼야
But if I have to,
Kramer's got my back.
신뢰하는 누군가가 있는건
좋은 일이네요
Must be nice having someone
who believes in you.
신뢰를 잃을 만한 일을 하지 않는거지
I never gave him
a reason not to.
러스티!
Rusty!
What's this about?
뭐야 이건?
벌써 새로 팔게 생긴거야?
You already have
a new piece to sell?
You asked to meet
in plain sight.
평범한 곳에서 만나자며
Could you pick somewhere
more public?
좀 더 대중적인 곳은 없었어?
네 헤어스타일이 너무 튀잖아
And your hair's
like a freaking flare.
이거 유전이라고
네 셔츠처럼 고를 순 없는거야
This is genetics.
That shirt is a choice.
왜 만나자고 한거야?
Why are we here?
내가 마지막에 팔았던
작품에 대해 물어보려고
This is about
the last piece I sold.
그거 어딨어?
Where is it?
내 직업관을 테스트 하는거야?
그거 모욕적인데
Questioning
my professional discretion?
- I'm insulted.
- Rusty, I need it back.
러스티, 그거 돌려 받아야 겠어
음, 그건 다른 얘기라고
Well, that's a different
conversation.
말해줄 수는 있지만
I can talk to the guy,
see if he'd be willing
그 사람이 주는
30%의 수수료는 어쩌라고?
to part with it for, say, a 30% profit?
긴급상황이야
This is an emergency.
어떻게 돌아가는지는 알지?
Do you know how this works?
난 중개인이야
I'm a middleman.
그 이름을 말해주면
다음번엔 손 떼야 해
I give you the name,
you cut me out the next time.
내 일의 전부가 이름을 알려주지
않는 것에 달려있다고
My entire job is dependent
on me not telling you
that information.
FBI가 그 그림을 찾고 있어
The FBI is looking
for that painting.
도움받기 위해 협박까지 하는거야?
슬프네
Now you're trying to scare me
into helping you? Sad.
Not sad.
그런거 아냐
긴급상황이야!
FBI가 왔다고
Urgent!
The feds are here!
정말이야, 모지?
Really, Mozzie?
"늙고 지친 연방 요원이 날 쫓는다"고?
Going with the old, tired
"G-men are after me" bit?
러스티, 가만히 있어!
러스티!
Rusty, stay where you are!
Rusty!
다이애나, 지원팀에게 브리언트 공원을
둘러 싸라고 말해줘
Diana, tell backup
to come around to Bryant Park.
Hey, look out!
좋아요. 제가 왼쪽, 요원님이
오른쪽을 맡으시겠어요?
All right, I'll take left,
you take right?
Peter?
- 요원님?
- 가
Go.
Hey!
Such a hurry!
어디야?
네 뒤에..
Hey.
FBI 는 왜 데리고 온거야?
Why'd you bring the suit?
FBI 가 계속 러스티를 감시하고 있었어
Look, the FBI
has been monitoring Rusty.
요원님이 내게 연락할 시간을
안 주더라고
Peter didn't give me
a chance to warn you.
- 정보는 얻었어?
- 아무것도 안 말해줬어
- Did you get the info?
- Rusty didn't tell me anything.
긍정적으로 보면, FBI에게도
아무것도 안 말할거야
On the upside, I'm assuming
he won't tell the FBI, either.
좋아, 그를 잡으러 가야겠어
All right, good.
I'll head him off.
뭐? 안돼!
가게 나두자고
What? No!
Let him go!
요원님이 날 쫓고 있어, 모즈
Peter is gunning for me, Moz.
러스티를 잡는데 도움을 주면
의심을 덜 하게 될꺼야
If I help him catch Rusty,
maybe he'll ease up
on his leash.
요원님이 널 보기 전에
얼른 도망가
Now get out of here
before he sees you.
잠깐만, 러스티의 폰이야
Hold on. Rusty's phone.
우리에 관련된건 삭제해놨어
I deleted any references to us.
완벽해. 고마워 모즈
Perfect.
Thank you, Moz.
다이애나, 지원팀은 어딨는거야?
Diana, where are my guys?
출구는 봉쇄됬어
This exit's closed.
러스티
Rusty...
드가와 그 구입자에 대해서
이야기 해봐야겠는데
We need to talk
about a man and a Degas.
구식 팀워크지만
좋아 할 수밖에 없다니까요
Got to love
good old-fashioned teamwork.
수갑을 채우자 마자
변호사와 얘기하겠다네요
He screamed for his lawyer
the second I put cuffs on him.
말을 꺼내면 그의 명성에
금이 간다는 걸 안거지
He knows talking
will kill his reputation.
압박할 게 필요해
We need leverage.
여기 있어요
러스티의 폰을 찾았어요
You have it.
Found Rusty's phone.
던져 버리더라구요
He must have tossed it.
최근 통화 목록을 보면
드가를 어디에 팔았는지 밝혀질꺼에요
His recent call list
should help us figure out
where he got the Degas.
분석팀으로 보내야겠네
We'll get this to E.R.T.
사무실에서 보자
자세한건 거기서 얘기하자고
Meet you back at the office.
We'll go over details.
좋아요
Sounds good.
닐이 범인을 잡는데
매우 도움이 되네
Your boy is very helpful
for our lead suspect.
그런 것 같네요
So it seems.
잠시만요!
기다려 주세요
Excuse me!
Hold the elevator please!
고마워요
Thank you.
크리스. 크리스 게이츠
Chris. Chris Gates.
매튜 요원님
Agent Matthews.
그때 이후 부터는
멜리사라고 불러도 돼요
Please. You can call me
Melissa after last time.
그래요. 멜리사.
어떻게 지냈어요?
Sorry. Melissa.
How are you?
- 잘지내요
- 네
- I'm good.
- Good.
인터폴까지 여기에 연루된건 몰랐네요
I didn't know they'd pulled in
Interpol for this.
음, 여기 있는걸요
Well, here I am.
버크 요원님을 만나러 가는 길인가요?
On your way to see Agent Burke?
네
Yes.
- 네
- 같이 가겠네요
- Yes.
- We'll go together.
잘..됬네요
Fan... tastic.
드가 일로 오신거죠?
I assume you're here
about the Degas?
크라머 요원님이 말해준 것만 알아요
I only know
what Kramer tells me.
- 당신을 믿어도 될까요?
- 무슨 일이에요?
- Can I trust you?
- What's wrong?
멜리사..
Melissa...
- 믿어도 될까요?
- 믿어봐요
- Can I trust you?
- Try me.
제가 하려는 말은..
What I am about to say...
젠장. 당신은 권한이 없겠네요
Damn it.
You're not authorized.
어떤 권한요?
Authorized for what?
상관 없겠네요
시간이 없으니
It doesn't matter.
There's no time.
여기 뉴욕 화이트칼라 부서에
첩자가 있어요
There is a mole
in the White Collar division
here in New York.
네?
What?
이 사무실에서 나오는
승인안된 신호를 발견했거든요
We intercepted an unidentified
transmission from this office.
누군가 잠수함의 도난당한
예술품들을 노리고 있어요
Someone here is trying to make
a play for the sub's stolen art.
그래서 인터폴이 수사하는 거구요?
And they've sent Interpol in
to investigate?
맞아요. 특별한 임무를 수행중이에요.
여기의 그 누구도 믿으면 안되요
Yes. I'm on special assignment.
No one here can be trusted.
As far as this office
is concerned,
이 사무실에선 제가
FBI에 빚진 컨설턴트로 되어있어요
I'm a recovery consultant
on loan to the bureau.
하지만 같이 술 마신 밤에는..
But the night
we had drinks--
부주의 했어요.
잠시 느슨해졌었죠
I was careless, all right?
I let my cover slip.
혼란하게 해서 미안해요
I'm sorry I got you
mixed up in this.
크리스..
Chris--
닐이라고 불러주세요
Call me "Neal."
Please.
술 마신건 후회하지 않아요
I definitely don't regret
the drinks, though.
매튜 요원
멀리 와줘서 감사하네요
Agent Matthews.
Thanks for making the trip.
물론이죠
이게 제 일인걸요
Of course.
That's the job.
크라머 요원님이 요청했던
모든 걸 가지고 왔어요
I have everything
that Agent Kramer requested.
좋아요.
닐을 만났군요
Great.
I see you've met Neal.
- 네
- 네, 닐과 저는
- Yeah.
- Yes, Neal and I
올라오면서 매우 흥미로운
얘기를 했었죠
had a very interesting
conversation on the ride up.
항상 그런건 잘해요
He's always good for that.
네 말이 맞았어
You were right.
러스티가 건 전화번호가
단서가 됬어
The numbers on Rusty's cell
gave us a lead.
도움이 되었다니 다행이네요
Glad I could help.
크라머 요원이 회의실에 있어
가자
Agent Kramer's in the conference room.
Come on up.
마티니 한잔 더 사야겠네요
I owe you another Martini.
러스티가 몇몇 전화번호를
지운 걸로 보인다
It looks like Rusty deleted
several numbers from his phone
닐이 찾기 전에 말야
before Neal found it.
불행히도, 드가를 누가
넘겼는지는 알 수 없어
Unfortunately, we don't know
who he bought the Degas from.
하지만 그림을 찾아낸다면
압박해서 알아낼 수 있어요
But if we find it,
we'll have leverage
to make him tell us
where he got it.
맞아
Yep.
좋은 소식은, 어디에
팔았는지는 알아 냈다는 거야
The good news is, we think
we know who he sold it to.
이 남자에게 몇 번의 전화를 했어
There were several calls
placed to this man.
엘리엇 리치몬드네요
That's Elliott Richmond.
암시장 불법 무기상입니다
He's a black-market
arms trafficker.
소문에 따르면 M240으로
재산을 늘렸다고 합니다
Rumor is he made a fortune
moving M240s.
그 재산을 예술품 구입에 썼나보군
A fortune he spends on art.
인상파에 대한 감수성이 있어
He's got a soft spot
for impressionists.
이런 놈들에게 예술품은 현금과 같지
Art is currency
for guys like this.
수십년간, 다수의 암시장 딜러들이
현금으로 거래하는 걸 멈췄어
Over the past decade, a majority
of black-market dealers
stopped trading in cash.
추적되기 쉽고
다루기 불편하기 때문이지
Too easy to trace,
too unwieldy.
더플백에 돈 다발을 옮기는 대신에..
Instead of carrying duffel bags
with millions in bank notes--
같은 가격의 그림으로
거래를 하는게 더 쉽죠
It's easier to trade a single piece
of art worth the same amount.
닐
Neal, rumor is
소문엔 네가 이런 지불과정에
대한 경험이 있다고 들었는데
you've had some experience
in this payment process.
자세한 사항은 민감한 문제라서요
Well, details are sensitive,
하지만 전해진 바에 의하면
그 도둑이 훔친 마넷을 거래했다네요
but the thief in mind
allegedly traded a Manet
for a batch
of stolen identities.
힘든 임무였죠
It was a tough assignment.
임무라고?
Assignment?
네, 웨슬리 가프리라고 밝혀졌어요
Yeah, the Wesley Godfrey cover
was blown.
리치먼드에 대해서는요?
What's our angle on Richmond?
75번가의 펜트하우스에 머물고 있어
Richmond keeps a penthouse
at 75 Wall.
뉴욕에 다른 부동산은 없고
예술품을 보는걸 좋아하지
He doesn't own any other
property in the city,
and he loves to look at his art,
그래서, 저기가 드가를
보관해 놓은 곳 일꺼야
so it's a good bet this is
where he's keeping the Degas.
이미 작전은 꾸며 놓았어
We've already set up
a buy with him.
멜리사, 부탁해
Melissa, if you'd be so kind.
2년 전에 독일에서
사건을 맡았을때 회수한 거야
Two years ago, I recovered this
while working a case
in Germany.
와우
Whoa!
서류가방을 통해 발사되는 MP5K 네요
This is an MP5K modified
to shoot through a briefcase.
Very rare. Civilians can't
get their hands on them.
매우 희귀한거지
일반인들은 손도 못대는 거야
리치몬드에게 말해놨어
이걸 보고 맘에 든다면
We've told Richmond
that if he likes what he sees,
몇백개라도 구해 줄 수 있다고말야
I can get him a couple hundred.
드가와 협상하기엔 충분한 가격일거야
That should be enough
to negotiate for a Degas.
- 직접 가시는거에요?
- 판매자로 위장할거고
- You're going in?
- I'm gonna pose as the seller,
다이애나가 지원해줄꺼야
and Diana will be my backup.
다이애나요?
Diana?
넌 총 싫어하잖아.
하지만 보다시피 다이애나는..
You hate guns,
and as we can all see, Diana...
좋아 죽죠
Kind of love 'em.
그럼 전 앉아서 구경만 하는거에요?
So I'm sitting this one out?
그렇지는 않네
Not exactly.
자네는 밴 안에 있을거야
You'll be in the van...
나와 함께 말이야
with me.
서류 가방안의 HK MP5 라
HK MP5 in a briefcase.
멋지군요
Classic.
방아쇠가 손잡이에 있지요
Trigger's in the handle.
걸어 다니면서도 서류가방을 통해
총을 쏠 수 있습니다
It'll fire through the briefcase
shell while you're walking.
아주 좋군요
얼마나 가지고 있다구요?
Very nice.
How many have you got?
이백개가 넘죠. 다 구입하시려면 비쌀겁니다
(gross : 144 개 한 묶음짜리)
Two gross, but this will
cost you. It's a rare item.
그 정도는 이해하죠
Oh, I understand that.
저 여자는 여기서 뭘 하는건진
이해 못하겠군요
What I don't understand
is what she's doing here.
제 보조 입니다
She assists me.
말은 못하나요?
Can't the lady
speak for herself?
제가 그의 근육이 되기도 하죠
The lady is also his muscle.
웃기군요
You're funny.
거래 해 볼까요
Let's talk.
베리건 요원이 인상적인데
Agent Berrigan seems impressive.
거의 피터 요원님 만큼 인상적이죠
Almost as impressive as Peter.
한가지 피터에 대해서
확실한게 있다면..
If there's one sure thing
about Peter,
마음에 두는게 있으면
확실히 수행한다는거야
he accomplishes
what he puts his mind to.
목표를 정하면
잡을 때 까지 계속 쫓지..
If he's got a target, he'll keep
pursuing till he hits it...
한 가운데를 노려
dead-center.
제가 묻고 싶은건..
I'll tell you what --
몇 백개를 가지고 와서
거래를 하겠다는 겁니까?
you bring me a gross,
and you've got yourself a deal.
그렇소. 하지만
현금이나 수표는 안받습니다
Done. But I don't do
cash or check.
나도 마찬가지요
Neither do I.
최근에 이 총과 교환할 만큼의
가치를 가진 물건을 구했죠
I have got a recently acquired
and very valuable item
that is worthy of these guns--
물론, 금전적으로 말해서 말이죠
financially speaking, of course.
어떤 물건인가요?
What kind of item?
무슨 일이죠?
What happened?
피터 요원은 네가 생각하는 것 만큼
널 파트너로 생각하지 않는 거겠지
Maybe Peter
doesn't consider you
as much of a partner
as you think.
내일 한 시 정각
Tomorrow. 1:00 sharp.
총을 가지고 오시죠
난 물건을 가지고 가겠소
You bring the guns.
I'll bring the item.
내일까지
Until tomorrow.
주변만 서성이며 일하는건
상당히 힘들 것 같아보이는데요
Must be hard to do your job when
you're kept out of the loop.
뭔가 알고 있는 것 처럼 보이는데요?
You seem to know something
about that, huh?
- Hey.
아까 무슨 일이 있었던거에요?
What happened today?
- 시계가 꺼졌더라구요
- 오
- Your watch cut out.
- Oh.
장비 고장이야. 가끔 발생하지
Equipment malfunctions.
It happens.
나보다 더 잘 알잖아
You know that
better than anyone.
제게 모든 걸 말하지 않는다는 거죠?
So you're not gonna
tell me everything, huh?
난 내 단서를 따르는거야
I'm following my leads.
네가 싫어한다면 어쩔 수 없어
If you don't like
where they go, too bad.
크라머 요원님이 말한대로네요
That's Kramer talking.
- 요원님을 지배하고 있어요
- 아냐
- He's the devil on your shoulder.
- No.
내가 왜 여기 있는지 상기시켜주지
He's reminding me why I'm here.
전 이 수사를 돕고 있다구요
I'm helping this investigation.
널 미술품 절도죄로 잡았을 때
네가 했던 말 생각나?
Do you remember
what you said to me
the day I first accused you
of stealing the art?
뭐였지, 닐?
What was it, Neal?
"증명 해 보세요"
"Prove it."
네가 말했던거, 조심해야 할꺼야
Be careful what you wish for.
행운을 빌게요
Then good luck.
멜리사
Melissa.
뭔가 떨어졌어요
You dropped something.
제가 집을께요
I'll get it.
Oh.
결국 크라머 요원님이
당신을 끌어들인 것 같군요?
Guess Kramer brought you in
the loop after all, huh?
고마워요
Thanks.
천만에요
You're welcome.
그래요, 내가 이 빌라들을 소유하고있죠
Why, yes, I do own these villas.
뭔가요? 섬이요?
What's that? The island?
맞아요. 그것도 제가
소유하고 있다고나 할까요
Yeah. I kind of own that, too.
물론이죠, 산호초 보여드릴까요?
Sure, I can show you
coral reef...
제 잠수함에서요
In my submersible.
문제가 생겼어
We got a problem.
그 문구에 저작권을 걸어야겠는데
We should maybe
copyright that phrase.
내일 한 시 정각에 리치몬드의
집을 수색할 예정이야
Peter put in an op order
to search Richmond's home
tomorrow at 1:00.
FBI 가 도착하기 전에
거기 도착 해야 해
We need to get there
before the feds.
밤에 만나자
Meet at place tonight.
멋져 보이네, 모지
Looking sharp, there, Mozzie.
켈러..
Keller...
뜻밖인데
Quelle surprise.
찾기 힘들더구만
You're a hard man
to track down.
난 항상 탈출구를 만들어 놓는다고
You should know I always
have an escape route.
내 다섯걸음 왼쪽에
A라는 일행이 있어
Five paces to my left
is the "A" train.
내 오른쪽엔 제리가 있고
To my right is Jerry,
고귀한 핫도그 파는 사람처럼
위장해서 날 지키고 있다고
a noble hot-dog vendor who would
gladly risk his life for mine.
내가 보기에는 여기 있는
셔츠들이 전부인 것 같은데
Looks to me
there's only one major exit
you're concerned with, given
these fancy shirts, here.
거의 날 죽일 뻔 했어, 모지
You almost killed me, Mozzie.
Hmm?
내 머리에 돈을 걸었더군
You put a price on my head.
그럼 내가 해야 할 건
소리 치는거고
Which means all
I have to do is scream
뉴욕의 사람들이
당신을 잡는거지
and New York closes in
to take you down.
네가 소리 치면, 물고기
내장 제거하는 것처럼 해주지
You scream,
I gut you like a carp,
그럼 네 일행에게
절름거리며 가게될꺼야
then hop the "A" train
five paces to your left.
제리가 널 그렇게 나두지 않을껄
Jerry would never
let you get that far.
용감한데, 모지.
제안 하나 하지
You're bold, Mozzie,
I'll give you that.
카프리는 절대 하지 못할
인정사정없는 선택을 해야 할꺼야
You make the kind
of ruthless choices
that Caffrey never would.
뭘 원하나, 켈러?
What do you want, Keller?
알면서 왜 물어봐
난 여기 정중하게 온거라고
You know what I want.
I'm here as a courtesy...
이게 네 보물을 지켜 낼
마지막 기회가 될꺼야
Which means
this is your last chance
to cut me in on your treasure.
당신이 무슨 말을 할지 알더라도
Even if I knew
what you were talking about,
대답은 항상 '아니오' 야
the answer would still be no.
확신 하나?
You're sure about that?
기억해, 난 예의바르게 물어봤어
Remember, I did ask nicely.
내가 원하는 걸 넘겨주도록
만들어야 겠네
Now I'm gonna have to make you
give me what I want.
어떻게?
How?
미리 말하면 재미 없잖아?
Why ruin the surprise?
즐겨봐
Enjoy.
스포츠 점수판이라고 생각하고
보고 있는 거야?
You'd think that thing
had sports scores on it.
닐의 추적장치 데이터를
확인하고 있어
I'm looking
at Neal's tracking data.
한 시간 동안
계속 그러고 있었어
Is that what you've been doing
for the last hour?
어디있는지 알아 내야 해
I need to know where he is.
자기, 월요일 10시가 다 됬어
Honey, it's almost 10:00
on a Monday.
이 시간에 어딜 가진 않을꺼야
I don't think
he's going anywhere.
그래, 확신 할 수 없어
아직은..
Yeah, I can't be too sure...
Not now.
모든 일이 잘 되면
내일 그림에 대해 밝혀질꺼야
All goes well, we'll recover
the painting tomorrow.
그러고 나면?
Then what?
사실을 알게 될꺼야
Then I'll know the truth.
닐이 실제로 한거지, 그렇지?
Neal really did it, didn't he?
갑자기 왜 그렇게 확신하는거야?
What's got you
suddenly so convinced?
자기가
You.
저번에 이만큼 집착했을 때
The last time
you obsessed this much,
그를 잡았잖아
you caught him.
왔네
Hey.
문제가 생겼어
We've got a problem.
네 말이 맞아.
그거 정말 저작권을 걸어야 겠어
You're right--
we should copyright that phrase.
켈러가 돌아왔어
Keller's back.
그리고 우리의 보물을 원하고 있어
And he wants our treasure.
뭐?
What?
모든 미국 정부와
지하세계 범죄자들의 반이 찾고 있는데
He's got the entire
U.S. government
and half the criminal
underworld looking for him.
바로 그거야.
머무르고 있다면
Exactly,
and if he's sticking around,
그건 뭔가 큰 일을
벌이려고 하는거야
it means he's planning
to do something big.
그 일이 벌어지기 전에
막아야 해
So we should split
before that happens.
아니, 드가 문제를 해결하고 난 뒤
켈러 문제를 걱정해야 해
No, we worry about Keller
after our Degas problem
is handled.
거의 위조 다 됬어
I'm almost done
with the forgery.
48시간이야 모즈.
시간 안에 해결하자
48 hours, Moz.
Let's make them count.
벌써 계획을 세웠구나
You've already got a plan.
FBI 가 급습해서 그림과 바꾸기 전에
10분이라는 시간이 있어
We'll have a 10-minute window
during the FBI raid
to swap the painting.
미안한데. 더 좋은
계획이 있는 줄 알았어
I'm sorry.
I assumed you had a good plan.
요원님이 내 뒤에 있는 한
이게 유일한 방법이야
With Peter on my back,
this is the only way.
그래, 그럼. 계속해봐
Okay, then. Proceed.
이건 리치몬드 아파트의 설계도야
All right, this is the layout
for Richmond's apartment.
펜트하우스 43층에 거주하지
He's the penthouse, 43rd floor,
접근 가능한 두 엘리베이터와
비상 계단이 있어
accessible by two elevators
and the fire stairs.
안쪽에, 리치몬드의 개인 무기고가 있다
Inside, Richmond's got
a personal arsenal,
그러니 조심해서 행동해야 해
so we have to tread carefully.
빨리 그를 잡아서
Take him down quickly
무기를 들 시간을
갖지 못하도록 해야 해요
so he doesn't have a chance
to grab a weapon.
리치몬드는 우리가 거래 하러
왔다고 생각할꺼야
Richmond thinks
we're there to deal.
다이애나, 나랑 같이 올라가고
Diana, you'll ride up with me.
존스, 네 팀은 비상계단을 맡아
Jones, your team
has the stairwell.
와우. 43층이나 되는데
운동 좀 하겠는데요
Wow. 43 floors.
Lucky I do cardio.
카프리는요?
What are you doing
with Caffrey?
카프리가 어디있는지
항상 알아야 해
I want to know where he is
at all times,
나랑 같이 갈꺼야
so he's coming with me.
요원님이 널 리치몬드에게
같이 데려간다면
If Peter's planning on taking
you up to Richmond's,
- 어떻게 작업이 진행되는거야?
- 날 데리고 가진 않을꺼야
- how is this gonna work?
- He won't be taking me up.
경비원들 데스크 바로 옆에
대기실이 있어
There's a holding room
right next to the guard's desk.
리치몬드의 방에 들어가기 전에
요원님이 거기 날 가둬놓게 할꺼야
I'll make sure
Peter locks me in there
before going up to Richmond's.
엘리베이터에서 거기를
관찰하기 좋은 곳이야
It's a clear shot
from there to the elevators.
그럼 조용한 신발이 필요하겠네
You'll need padded shoes.
- 그리고 엘레베이터 통제해
- 좋아
- And your elevator-override box.
- Okay.
요원님이 리치몬드에게 도착하기
전까지 시간을 벌 수 있겠지?
It'll buy me time
to hit Richmond
before Peter gets there?
그게 벌수 있는 전부 다야
That's all it's gonna buy you.
계단에도 있을꺼라구
They'll be on the stairs.
아래로 내려갈 다른 방법이 필요해
You'll need another way down.
알아
I know.
내려 갈 방법이 없는데
Uh, there is no other way down.
알아
I know.
드가를 회수하는 곳 근처에
닐을 두겠다는 건가?
You're keeping Neal close
while you go in for the Degas?
내 손에 있는 그림을 봤을때
그의 표정을 보고 싶어요
I want to watch his expression
when he sees the painting
in my hand.
오늘 밤에 미리 그쪽에 갈
가능성은 없나?
Any chance he goes
for the place tonight?
없어요, 추적장치 데이터를
확인하는 팀이 있어요
No, I've got a team monitoring
his tracking data.
하지만 그게 뭔가
안 꾸민다는걸 의미하진 않지
That doesn't mean
he's not planning something.
물론 그렇겠죠
I'm sure he is.
드가의 복사본과 장비들을 리치몬드의
장소에 어떻게 옮기지?
How are we gonna get
the copy of the Degas
and all the other stuff up to
Richmond's in the first place?
네가 하면 되지
You're gonna do it.
어떻게?
How?
바주카가 필요해
We're gonna need a bazooka.
오
Oh.
AT4 무반동 바주카를 보고 계십니다
You are looking
at an AT4 recoilless rifle.
SAAB 제품이고 미국과 스웨덴
군대에서 사용되었죠
Made by Saab, fielded by U.S.
and Swedish forces.
작년 여름에 아프가니스탄에서
유명했었어요
Very popular in Afghanistan
last summer.
몇 개나 가지고 있죠?
How many do you have?
200 개 정도입니다
We'll go with 200.
어디서 얻었는지 물어봐도 될까요?
Should I be asking
how you got them?
트럭에서 떨어졌다고만 해두죠
Let's just say
they fell off a truck.
트럭에서 떨어졌는데 어떻게
부서지지 않았단걸 알 수 있죠?
How do I know nothing broke
falling off that truck?
이걸 견본품으로 생각하시고
Oh, consider this a floor model.
확인해보시고
마음에 드시면
Test it out,
and if you like it,
나머지 199개에 대해서 이야기 하죠
we can talk
about the other 199.
사실 여기서는
테스트 하지 못하네요
Obviously I can't test it here.
그럼 천천히 하세요
Oh, take your time.
연락 드릴게요
You know, I'll be in touch.
해보세요, 즐겨보세요
Enjoy. Enjoy.
좋아
Okay.
엘리베이터는 내가
컨트롤 하고 있어, 닐
The elevators are mine, Neal.
나머지는 네게 달렸어
The rest is up to you.
팀 원은 계단에 위치했습니다
Team one in position
on the stairs.
고마워, 존스
우린 들어간다
Thanks, Jones.
We're moving in.
알겠습니다
I got it.
이걸로 뭐 할 생각이었나?
What are you planning
to do with this?
항상 준비된게 좋잖아요, 그죠?
Always be prepared, right?
그래
Right.
FBI입니다. 펜트하우스를
수사할 영장이 있습니다
FBI. We have a warrant
to search the penthouse.
피터 버크 요원입니다
Agent Peter Burke.
적대적인 목격자가 있습니다
I have a hostile witness
on my hands.
제가 윗층에 올라가서 조사할 동안
Do you have a storage room
or an office that I can borrow
잠시 빌릴 수 있는 창고나
사무실이 있나요?
while I'm conducting
my business upstairs?
네, 바로 저쪽입니다.
보여드리죠
Yes, sir. Right over there.
I'll show you.
왜 그러세요. 요원님
여기에 절 가두실 순 없어요
Oh, come on, Peter.
You cannot lock me in here.
보고 있어봐
Watch me.
어떤 상황에서도
저자가 여길 벗어나선 안됩니다
Under no circumstances
is he to leave.
신체적 문제 없고
He has no medical condition,
물도 많이 마셧고
화장실도 이미 갔다왔어요
he's had enough water,
and he's been to the bathroom.
불러도, 대답하지 마세요
If he calls you, don't answer.
도움을 요청 하더라도
그냥 묵인하세요
If he requests anything,
don't acquiesce.
아시겠죠? 제가 저 문을
열 수 있는 유일한 사람이라는겁니다
Am I clear? I am the only person
to open that door.
나중에 다시 오겠습니다
I'll be back down later.
닐은 잘 처리 하셨나요?
Everything okay with Neal?
아무데도 못 갈꺼야
He won't be going anywhere.
거기 있어, 모즈?
You there, Moz?
이름을 말하면 안돼, 닐.
웁스
No names, Nea--
Oops.
알았어
Got it.
뭐야
What the hell?
갇혔어요.
존스, 약간 지체될거 같아. 기다려줘
We're stuck.
Jones, we've got a delay. Stand by.
경비에게 말해봐
Call down to the guards.
빨리 이 엘리베이터가
움직이도록 해야 돼
We need this elevator
moving immediately.
'방해 작전'이 수행 중이야
Operation Fedibuster
is in play.
좋아. 때가 되면 말해줘
All right.
Tell me when.
그래요, 엘리베이터에 갇혔다구요
Yeah, we're stuck.
확실한가요?
Are you sure?
- 뭐요?
- 장난하는 건가요? 확실합니다
- What?
- Are you kidding me? Yes, we're sure.
엘리베이터 작동하게 해줘요. 얼른요
Get this elevator moving.
Come on.
지금이야!
Now!
조금만 참으세요
You'll have to be patient.
몇 초 걸릴거에요
This could take a second.
얼른 엘리베이터 동작하게 해줘요
Get this elevator moving.
Come on!
지금 문 열게
Opening door now.
닐, 서둘러
Neal, hurry up.
아찔했어
That was close.
심장이 멎을 뻔 했어
It got my pulse going.
올리던지 내리던지 하라구요
Get us up or get us down.
어떻게 하든지 간에 상관없어요
빨리 꺼내 주세요
I don't care what you do, just
get us out of this elevator now.
이해를 못하시네요
You don't understand.
시스템을 재부팅 했습니다.
초기화 하는데 시간이 걸린다구요
I'm rebooting the system, ma'am.
It takes time to initialize.
빨리 끝내주세요
Get it done.
그림을 어디에 숨겼는지 알겠어?
Hey, you know where
he hid the painting?
생각이 있어
I have an idea.
찾았네
Found it.
서둘러, 닐. 시간이 없어
Hurry, Neal.
Your time is running out.
드디어
Finally.
존스, 올라간다
Jones, we're on our way.
알았음
Roger that.
닐, 빠져 나와야 돼
Neal, get out of there!
펜트하우스에 근접했어
어서 빠져 나와야 돼
They've reached the penthouse.
Get out of there.
갑니다!
Coming!
- 들어오시죠
- 먼저 가시죠
- Come on in.
- After you.
총은 가져 오셨나요?
You didn't bring the guns?
아니요. 대신 이 영장을
가지고 왔죠
No. We brought
this warrant instead.
- 오
- FBI, 피터 버크 요원입니다
- Ohh.
- Peter Burke, FBI.
존스, 문제 없다
Jones, we're clear.
엘리엇 리치몬드
당신을 불법 무기 밀매로 체포합니다
Elliott Richmond,
you're under arrest
for illegal arms trafficking.
닐, 요원님과 다이애나가
리치몬드와 함께있어
Neal, Peter and Diana
are with Richmond.
여길 빠져나가야 겠다
행운을 빌어
I'm getting out of here.
Good luck.
아래에서 보자고, 모즈
See you on the other side, Moz.
- 정확한 착륙이지
- 난 술 한잔 해야겠어
- Nailed the landing.
- I need a drink.
시간 좀 걸리셨네요
무슨 문제 있었나요?
Took you a while.
Run into some problems?
리치몬드는 싸워보지도 않고
항복 했어
Richmond went down
without a fight.
찾아 내셨군요
You found it.
속단 하지는 마
Don't jump to any conclusions.
크라머 요원님이 살펴 볼꺼야
Kramer still needs to weigh in.
알았어요
All right.
아직 감정 중인가요?
Any verdict yet?
일정한 간격을 유지하고
This is consistent
with the period
두꺼운 색에 어두운
팔레트가 쓰였어
where his dark palette
gave way to bold colors.
붓 터치 각도는
오른쪽으로 살짝 기울어져 있어
The strokes angle
slightly to the right.
So it's real?
진품인가요?
오
Ohh.
서명이 너무 희미해
The signature is dead on.
드가는 말년에 시력을 잃었었죠
Degas was losing his sight
toward the end.
여기 아직 산뜻한..
There's a crispness --
닐, 빠져 있어
Neal, stay out of this.
아냐, 아냐. 닐이 맞아
유화물감이 진품 여부를 말해준다고
No, no, he's quite right.
But the oil is the real tell.
진품처럼 보이려고
To make a work look authentic,
아마인 유화 물감에 착색제가 둘러져있어
pigments are bound
with linseed oil,
50년 전에 마른 것
처럼 보이려고 말이야
which takes roughly
50 years to dry.
그럼 결국 표면이 갈라지면서
유화 물감이 증발하게 되지
When that finally happens,
the oil starts evaporating,
causing the surface to crack.
하지만..
However...
제가 좀?
Yeah?
보게나
Please.
감사합니다
Thank you.
그렇네요
Yeah.
작은 갈라짐들이 아직
미숙합니다
These micro-cracks
are slightly immature
100년 된 작품으로는
보기 힘들죠
for a work that's supposed to be
over a hundred years old.
좋은 안목이야, 미스터 카프리
Good eye, Mr. Caffrey.
조금만 더 구웠다면
나도 속을 뻔 했네
Little more time in the oven,
and it would have had me fooled.
그럼 위조라는 거군요
So it's a forgery.
으흠
Mm-hmm.
음
Mm.
유감이네요, 요원님
I'm sorry, Peter.
얼마나 기대하셨는지 알아요..
I know how much
you wanted this.
피티..
Petey...
그래도 불법 무기상이랑
몇몇 도난 당했던 그림들도 회수했어
We took down an arms dealer
and recovered a number
of missing paintings.
그래도 성공한거야
This is still a win.
진품일 꺼라고 확신했는데..
I thought for sure
it was the real thing...
보물은 밖에 있고 말이죠..
That the treasure
was out there.
진실을 찾는건 널
좋은 요원으로 만들어주지
Searching for the truth
is what makes you a good agent.
항상 잘 할수는 없지 않는가
You can't always be right.
사실, 가장 힘든 건
네가 틀렸다는 걸 인정하는 거야
In fact, the hardest thing
to do is admit you're wrong,
내가 닐에 대해서 생각하는 것
처럼 말이야
like I seemed to be about Neal.
닐이 변했다고 생각하시나요?
You think he's changed?
아직 확신을 가지고
말 할 수는 없지만..
I can't say it with conviction
that he's reformed yet...
닐이 여기 있길 원한다는 건
말 할 수 있지
But I can tell you
he wants to be here.
흠
Hmm.
뭐 좀 찾았나요?
Find something interesting?
안녕하세요, 크리스
Hi, Chris.
비밀 임무를 하기 위해
노력 많이 하셨더군요
You went all out
for your undercover assignment.
사무국에 잘 적응 하셨더라구요
Really settled into the Bureau.
넥타이 서랍장도 멋지구요
The tie drawer's a nice touch.
위장하는게 제 전문이죠
Maintaining cover
is my specialty.
오, 알아요
Oh, I know.
존스 요원이
Agent Jones told me
당신과 같이 일하는게 얼마나
즐거운 지 말해주더군요
how much he's enjoyed working
with you all this time.
좋아요. 아셨나보네요
All right.
You caught me.
전 제가 말한 사람은 아니에요
I'm not who I said I was.
물론 아니겠죠. 당신은 닐 카프리죠.
사기와 위조로 악명높거든요
No. You're Neal Caffrey,
infamous con man and forger.
잘못을 인정할게요
Guilty as charged.
얼마나 이 비밀을
지킬 수 있을 거라 생각하나요?
How long did you think
you could keep this up?
오래 갈꺼라는 생각은 안했어요
그냥 시간이나 벌어볼까 했죠
Not long,
but I needed to buy some time,
and it was the only play I had.
딱 한번 그랬던 거에요
멜리사, 피터 요원님과 같이
Melissa, working with Peter
일했던건 가장 멋진
일 중에 하나에요
has been one of the best things
that's ever happened to me.
하지만 절 계속 따돌리더라구요
어떤 느낌인지 알잖아요
But he started cutting me out.
You know how that feels.
날 믿지 않았다구요
He wasn't trusting me.
상상이 가네요
Imagine that.
왜 그래야 했는지 알아야 했어요
내가 고칠 수 있게요
I needed to know why
so I could fix it.
당신을 끌여들여서
미안해요
I'm sorry
I brought you into this.
분명한건, 제가 모든걸
크라머 요원님께 말할거라는 거에요
Obviously, I'll have to tell
Kramer everything.
물론이죠.
우리 모두 진실을 말해야죠
Of course.
We'll tell him the truth.
모든 진실을 말이죠
The whole truth.
내가 크라머 요원님께
If I tell him I told you
마티니 마시면서 말했던
유보트의 적하 목록의 존재를 말하면
about the existence of the
U-Boat manifest over Martinis,
내 경력은 끝이에요
my career is over.
당신도 이미 알고 있었겠죠
And you know that.
진짜 '닐 카프리' 답군요
You really are Neal Caffrey.
'화이트 칼라'에 오신걸 환영합니다
Welcome to White Collar.
당신이 일하는거, 상당히
인상적이었어요
It was impressive
watching you work.
당신도요
Likewise.
누가 저 그림을 위조 했건 간에
Whoever forged that painting
우리의 일을 더 흥미롭게
만들어 줄걸세
is gonna make our work
a whole lot more interesting.
왜 그런가요?
Why's that?
왜냐하면, 내가 본 것 중에
가장 최고의 솜씨였거든
Because it's the best
I've ever seen.
우리가 해냈어, 모즈
We did it, Moz.
FBI가 우리를 추적하는걸 멈췄다고
The FBI is off our trail.
네가 좋은 포도주를 거절하는 건 처음 보네
(Bordeaux : 브로도 포도주)
I've never known you
to pass up a good Bordeaux.
뭐 알아차린거 없어?
Notice anything?
왜 그래
Come on.
우리의 승리를 잠시 즐길 수 없어?
Can we please enjoy our victory?
닐, 난 정말 많이 참아왔다고
Neal, I've been really patient.
선택을 해야 할 시간이야
But it's time for you
to make a choice.
떠날꺼야, 아니면 머물꺼야?
Do you want to leave or not?
못 떠나
No.
여기서의 인생을 포기할
준비가 되어 있지않아
There are things about this life
I'm not ready to give up.
네 인생이 어떻게
될지도 모르는데도?
Do you even know
what this life is anymore?
내 말은, 넌.. 구속되어있잖아
I mean, you're... on a leash.
아직 감옥에 있는 거라구
You're still in prison.
그거 스톡홀름 증후군이야
(Stockholm syndrome : 인질이 범인에게
호감을 나타내는 현상)
You have Stockholm syndrome.
I can always
walk out that door, Moz.
언제든지 나갈 순 있어, 모즈
하지만 다시 돌아 올 수는 없잖아
I can never walk back in.
음, 그럼 넌 선택을 한거네
Well, then,
you've made your choice.
난 항상 우리 사이가
해피엔딩이라고 생각햇어
I always thought ours
would be a happy ending.
해피 엔딩을 원한다면
그건..
If you want a happy ending,
it depends--
이야기를 끝내는 거다. 알아
on where you stop the story.
오손 웰즈가 한 말이지
(Orson Welles : 미국 영화 감독)
Yeah, Orson Welles.
또 보자, 닐..
I'll see you around, Neal.
넌 네 자신을 속이고 있는거야
You're fooling yourself
그게 정말 너라고
생각하고 있다면 말야
if you think this is
who you really are.
자기, 정말 이러다 미치는거 아냐?
Honey, you're gonna
drive yourself crazy.
뭔가 놓치고 있어. 엘
I'm missing something, El.
할 만큼 했어
You've looked
as hard as you can.
오늘은 그만 쉬어
There's nothing more
to find today.
하지만 뭔가 있어
마땅한 증거가 나오면..
But there will be, and when
the right evidence surfaces...
그게 닐의 얼굴을
날려 버릴까봐 걱정이야
...I'm afraid this will
all blow up in Neal's face.
그가 뭔가 했던간에
그건 이미 벌어진거야
Whatever mess he made,
he made it.
그리고 그게 나오면
And if it comes out,
닐이 스스로 처리 해야 할꺼야
he's gonna have to clean it up.
그래서.. 뭐?
So... what?
집에 와서..
So come home...
저녁을..
have dinner...
자기가 좋아하는
맥주 마시면서 좀 쉬어
relax with a bottle
of your favorite beer...
그리고 다시 일하구
and continue working
on the case,
왜냐면 자기는..
because you are...
워커홀릭이라서?
A workaholic?
..피터버크
고고학자잖아
...Peter Burke,
the archeologist.
고마워, 자기
곧 갈게
Thanks, honey.
I'll be home soon.
응
Okay.
버크 요원
Agent Burke.
늦게까지 일하는구만
Working late again.
집요한데.
그건 내가 놓아둔거야
You're persistent,
I'll give you that.
- 켈러
- 연출 좀 했어, 미안하군
- Keller.
- Pardon the theatrics.
하지만 어떤 상황에서도
But under the circumstances,
이런 대화를 만나서 하진 못하지
we can't be having
this conversation in person.
이해 할꺼라 믿어
I'm sure you understand.
뭘 원하나, 켈러?
What do you want, Keller?
당신의 도움이 필요하지
I need your help.
내 도움이라
My help.
자수 하면
내가 할수 있는걸 찾아보지
Turn yourself in.
I'll see what I can do.
그래, 하지만 그렇게는 못해
버크 요원
Yeah, I don't think
I can do that, Burke.
그래서 말인데
But I tell you what--
날 도와주면, 당신을 도와 주지
if you help me, I can help you.
당신이 생각하는것 보단
상호 관심사가 많을꺼야
Our interests are
more mutual than you think.
어떻게 아는 거지?
And you know this how?
난 보물을 봤거든
Because I've seen the treasure.
그래, 카프리가 가지고 있다고
Yeah, your boy Caffrey's got it.
당신은 그걸 원하고
And you want it.
난 게임 별로 안 좋아해, 버크 요원
I'm a sucker for the game, Burke.
그래서, 도와 줄꺼냐, 말꺼냐?
So, you gonna help me or what?
내가 왜 당신을 도와야 하지?
Why would I help you?
좋은 질문이야
That's a good question.
집에 가서
How about you go home
좋아하는 맥주 마시면서
좀 쉬는거에 대해서
and relax with a bottle
of your favorite beer
어떻게 생각해?
and think about it?
혼자 시간 좀 보내야 할거야
You could use some alone time.
요원님
Boss.
이웃이 뉴져지 번호판의
블랙밴을 보았다고 합니다
Neighbors saw a black van,
Jersey plates.
납치할 땐 살아 있었답니다
She was alive
when they took her.
주요 교차로와 도로를
검문하고 있습니다
We're all over
major transportation centers.
시내를 몰래
빠져나갈 수는 없을겁니다
He won't get out of the city
without us knowing.
요원님
Peter.
그놈이 내 와이프를 납치했어
He took my wife.
영자막 : Sync by Gatto, corrected by gloriabg
www.addic7ed.com
한글자막 : EzLoves
Sync by Gatto, corrected by gloriabg
www.addic7ed.com